lifetechnologies.com 2011-10-05

# Privacy Policy | Life Technologies

##  Life Technologies Corporation 

Welcome to [lifetechnologies.com](http://www.lifetechnologies.com/), [Invitrogen.com](http://www.invitrogen.com/) and [AppliedBiosystems.com](http://www.appliedbiosystems.com/) (and permutation web pages that provide a direct link to this Privacy Policy – collectively the “Sites”), which are owned and operated by Life Technologies Corporation (“Life Technologies” or “we”), 5791 Van Allen Way, Carlsbad, CA, 92008, USA. This Privacy Policy is designed to explain our practices regarding the collection and use of information received from you and/or your company.

The Sites provide an opportunity for investors, prospective employees, and other adults to learn more about our company. The Sites are particularly geared to our customer base – biotechnology researchers and life scientists – and to providing them with content, products, and services focusing on their industry, to the role they play in their organizations, and to helping them accomplish biological procedures faster, more reliably, and in a cost-efficient manner. Your use of the Sites is subject to this Privacy Policy, which you may at any time print or download (or request a printed copy by contacting us as specified below). We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the revised policy at this location. 

#### Consent and Data Transfer:

**By giving your personal information to us, which includes information furnished during a pre-registration, online order or other registration or data capture process, you agree that we may collect and use such personal information and other information in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.**

**For our customers in Switzerland and the European Union, please note that Life Technologies (as a US based company) operates also through its direct and indirect subsidiaries in countries outside of Switzerland and the European Union (including the US) and may involve certain third parties (see section Third Parties below). If you use this Site, all information, including personal information, will be transferred to Life Technologies (including subcontractors that may be maintaining and/or operating our Sites) in the United States and elsewhere and may be transferred to third parties that may be located anywhere in the world (see section Third Parties below). Although this may include recipients of information located in countries where there may be a lower level of legal protection for your personal information than in your location country, we will protect your information in accordance with requirements applicable to your information. By using this Site, you unambiguously consent to the transfer of your personal information and other information to the United States and elsewhere for the purposes and uses described herein.**

#### How we collect information about you:

**Personally identifying information.** When you register via this Site, you will be asked to provide personally identifying contact information (e.g., name, organization, address, phone number, e-mail address, fax number, and so on) and other information. On this Site, for example, we may collect and retain personally identifying and other information from you in a number of ways, such as when you place an order, request e-mail updates or other information, complete customer surveys, submit a feedback or contact form, or provide a resume. Information about particular transactions, such as product purchases over the website, is maintained in our databases in the same or similar manner as such information is maintained for transactions which are done by telephone, fax, etc. If any third parties, including any companies owned by Life Technologies, provide information to us about you, we may combine that information with other information we have about you, and if and to the extent we do, we will treat such combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**E-mail address.** Your e-mail address is used to raise and respond to issues and inquiries of all types and to keep in contact with you generally. It is also used to distribute information about us and market our products and services as described herein.

Use of cookies and website data. This Site collects various information from you in the course of your navigation of the Site, such as the URL of the site you just came from, the browser version you use, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, IP ports, date/time of access, size of data transferred, pages you visit, and other “clickstream” data. We are typically not able to relate such data to you as an individual if you merely browse our Site and do not disclose your identity to us, e.g., in connection with a registration. We also use "cookies" to enhance your Site visit. A “cookie” is information either temporarily or permanently stored in a file on your computer. You can set your internet browser to reject cookies (refer to your internet browser instructions if you wish to do so), but that may limit your use of some convenience features at this Site.

#### How we use information about you:

We use information collected by clickstream data collection and cookies to store your preferences, improve web site navigation, make personalized features and other services available to you, compile and analyze aggregate statistics and trends, and otherwise help administer and improve the Site. Where you provide registration information, cookies can also be used to identify you when you log onto the Site or portions of the Site.

Except as otherwise stated, we may use information we collect from you and others to respond to your request, improve the content, services, and products that we provide, customize this Site to your preferences, communicate information to you (where you have not expressed a preference otherwise), for our marketing and research analysis, and for other purposes identified to you. Some marketing and research analysis is conducted by third parties providing data collection and analysis services under contract with us, utilizing anonymous data collected from cookies. As noted above, you can reject such cookies by following your browser’s instructions. We reserve the right to make full use of information that is not in personally identifiable form. 

From time to time, we use contact information obtained via this Site to send e-mail and postal mail supplying customers with the most recent product and service information. as well as other information we think may be useful to you. If you order products or services via our Site, we may contact you by e-mail to send you information about your order (e.g., order confirmations, shipment notifications, etc.). We may also contact Site visitors via e-mail regarding their account status, and about changes to any relevant agreements or policies. We sometimes also use this data to establish a profile for your company, or collectively for some or all of our customers, to help us make business decisions, such as what kinds of new products we should be developing. We will also use it for other internal business purposes including aggregating information, data warehousing and mining, cross matching databases and pooling data for effective data management, to understand your needs, improve security of data, for statistical analysis, devising, deploying and measuring marketing campaigns and group wide sharing and for such and other reasonable business purposes and operational efficiency improvement. We may remove information when it becomes out of date or inaccurate or when properly requested by you (subject to any legal duty or requirement we may have to preserve it).

In connection with our customer rewards programs and/or other promotions, we use the information you submit to maintain your account, measure the benefits for our business and pursue other legitimate business purposes as described in this Privacy Policy and in the terms and conditions (where applicable) for the program or promotion.

#### How we share your information: 

**Third parties.** Life Technologies does not provide the personally identifiable information you supply to us to outside mailing lists. We may share information about you with employees, affiliates, successors, and agents/representatives (for example, consultants), which are required to treat the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Except as specifically described in this Privacy Policy, we will not, without your specific prior consent, sell, trade or transfer your information to unaffiliated third parties other than authorized third parties (such as, for example, contractors supporting operation of this Site) and other third parties involved in the distribution chain (e.g., vendors, service providers, principals for whom we act as agents or subcontractors), which may need access to some of your personal information in order to directly or indirectly fulfill a contractual obligation with you or for some other legitimate purpose. We oblige such third parties to comply with our privacy policy, and limit their access and use of your personal information. 

**Mergers/acquisitions.** In the event of any prospective or actual merger, business or asset sale, divestiture, other changes in control or financial status, or re-organization we may share or transfer personal information with the other party or parties involved. We will require the recipient to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Disclosures required by law.** Occasionally, we may be required by law enforcement, government contract administrators, and/or judicial authorities to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate judicial, governmental or regulatory authorities under applicable law, regulation or the terms of government contracts. We will disclose personally identifiable information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or if required to co-operate with law enforcement investigations or government contract compliance reviews. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful to the extent permitted by law.

####  How we protect your information:

We take reasonable technical and organizational steps to safeguard the information you provide to us and protect it from unauthorized access, loss, destruction or alteration. For example, web page elements transmitting personal or financial information are encrypted from your client PC to our servers (which are located in the United States to the extent data on Canadian registered website visitors is concerned) using the standard known as SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). Beyond the SSL encryption your data is protected once it reaches our network through the use of secure network firewalls. Portions of your data may also be encrypted on our storage server for additional security. 

Because no system is 100% secure or error-free despite taking commercially reasonable steps, Life Technologies and its affiliates do not guarantee, and you should not expect, that information you provide shall remain private under all circumstances. It is your responsibility to safeguard any passwords, ID numbers, or other special access features associated with your use of the Site.

#### Opting out:

If you do not wish to receive certain communications from us, or our affiliates or representatives, you may opt out by: (1) declining the service offered when registering or at other information collection points on the Site, or (2) informing us that you no longer wish to receive such communications. We will comply with such requests unless such communications from us are required by law or contract or do not require your consent under applicable laws. If you opt out of certain communications, you may not be able to access certain of our products or services. If you would like to opt-out of receiving communications from affiliates or other third parties with whom we shared data in accordance with this policy, please contact such third parties directly.

#### Access, blocking, deletion and correction of information you provide:

You may at any time request access to a summary of your personal information held by us, and request corrections or updates to that information. We will make reasonable efforts to respond promptly to such requests for information in accordance with local laws. Our response to such requests may be limited to information under our direct control. 

Please notify us of any changes in your name, address, title, telephone number or e-mail address. You can correct your personally identifiable information yourself by accessing your online profile, or by contacting us to request changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of certain transaction information, such as past purchases, and other similar information, for legal compliance purposes, we may not be able to delete certain information. If information we hold appears to be inaccurate we will block its use until the position is verified to our satisfaction. If you have any questions relating to this Privacy Policy or relating to the transfer of your personal data, please contact us at your local office. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not provide us with your information.   

#### Other web sites: 

This Site contains links to the web sites of other organizations. Life Technologies is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other web sites, and unless otherwise specified, does not imply any relationship, sponsorship, or affiliation between Life Technologies and these linked sites, or adoption or approval of the content of such sites. Since we do not control these web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on those, and all, third party web sites. 

#### Children's Privacy: 

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 18. 

#### How to contact us:

For any requests or questions related to this Privacy Policy, or if you have concerns about how information you provide to Life Technologies is being used, please contact us at the following address: **[communications@lifetech.com](mailto:communications@lifetech.com)**. This Privacy Policy is effective December 1, 2010. 

#### Revisions to Privacy Policy:

Please check back for material revisions to this Policy, which will be described here.
